(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-20T02:14:33.399630",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
もっと もっと
More, and more...
もっと もっと...
鏡よ教えて
Mirror, mirror, tell me,
私の証はどこにあるんだろう
where can I find the proof of my existence?
分からない 分からないよ
I don't know, I just don't know.
周りと比べたってさ
Comparing myself to others
虚しくなるだけ
only leaves me feeling empty.
あぁ ノイズが海鳴りのように
Ah, the noise, like the rumble of the ocean,
ナミダを奪う
steals away my tears.
切り取った風景を
The scenes I've captured,
道しるべにしよう
I'll make them my guiding light.
そうだ 傷ついた感情も
That's right, even these wounded feelings,
連れて行くから
I'll take them all along with me.
どアニメ宣言！JOYSOUND
Super Anime Declaration! JOYSOUND
アニメにハマって 歌いたくなっちゃった
I got into anime and really felt like singing!
推しのシーン見ながら カラオケ歌えるなんて...
To be able to sing karaoke while watching scenes of my fave...
尊すぎてつらい！
It's so precious, I can't handle it!
歌いたい曲見つけよう！
Let's find the song you want to sing!
JOYSOUND！
JOYSOUND!
ねぇ、今日はどこ行く？
Hey, where should we go today?
Yahoo!カーナビ「推しドラ」好評販売中！
Yahoo! Car Navi "Oshidora" now on sale!
今なら両方購入で、兎田ぺこらとの掛け合いボイスが聴ける！
If you buy both now, you can hear dialogue voice lines with Usada Pekora!
AZKiと一緒にドライブしよう！
Let's go on a drive with AZKi!
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon
Attention ご来場のお客様へ
Attention to All Attendees
ライブグッズ 2次販売決定!!
Live Goods Second Wave Sales Confirmed!!
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon
演出の都合上、照明の点滅にご注意ください
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
声出し応援OKです
Cheering loudly is ok.
ライブグッズ 2次販売決定!!
2nd round of live merchandise sales confirmed!
本日は、AZKi SOLO LIVE 2025 "Departure" にご来場いただき、ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming to AZKi SOLO LIVE 2025 "Departure" today!
こんこんこんこん、こんあずきー！
Kon-kon-kon-kon, Kon-AZKi!
あ、みんな元気がいいですね！
Ah, everyone is so energetic!
右手にマイク、左手に地図、あなたのハートをゼロゲッサー！AZKiでーす！
Mic in my right hand, map in my left hand, Geoguessr of your heart! I'm AZKi!
最後までライブを楽しんでいただくために、いくつかご案内させていただきます。
To ensure everyone can enjoy the live concert until the end, I have a few announcements.
公演中の撮影、録音、録画機材の使用は固くお断りいたします。
Taking photos, audio recording, and using video recording equipment during the show are strictly prohibited.
館内は禁煙となっております。喫煙はご遠慮ください。
Smoking is prohibited inside the venue. Please refrain from smoking.
万が一、具合が悪くなってしまった場合は無理をせず、近くのスタッフへお知らせください。
If you feel unwell, please do not push yourself and notify a nearby staff member.
会場内でのモッシュ、ダイブ、ステージにものを投げ込むなど、他のみんなの迷惑になったり、公演を妨げる行為は一切禁止です！
Moshing, diving, throwing objects onto the stage, or any action that disturbs others or disrupts the show is strictly forbidden!
ルールを守って、盛り上がってください！
Please follow the rules and have a great time!
えらい！
Good job!
尚、本公演は映像配信および写真撮影用のカメラが会場内に入り、客席が映り込む場合があります。
Additionally, cameras for live streaming and photography will be present, and the audience may be captured on camera.
これからの映像や写真はプロモーションなどに使用される可能性がありますので、あらかじめご了承ください。
Please note in advance that these videos and photos may be used for promotional purposes.
はい！えらい！
Yes! Good job!
また、ライブのハッシュタグは #AZKiと未来へ です！
Also, the official hashtag for today's live is #AZKitomiraihe!
ハッシュタグを使って、たくさん盛り上げてくれると嬉しいです！
I'd be so happy if you could use the hashtag and post lots to hype things up!
お願いします！
Please do!
それでは、開演までもう少しです！
Well then, there's just a little bit of time left until the show starts!
みんなの声、いっぱい聞かせてねー！
Let me hear lots of your loud cheers!
AZKi SOLO LIVE 2023 Departure
もっと
More...
鏡よ教えて
Mirror, mirror, tell me,
私の
about my...
私は
I wonder...
どこにあるのだろう
...where I am supposed to be.
分からない 分からないよ
I don't know, I just don't know.
周りと比べたってさ 虚しくなるだけ
Comparing myself to others only makes me feel empty.
あの雑音が海鳴りのように涙を奪う
That noise strips away my tears like the roaring sea.
切り取った風景を道標にしよう
Let's make this captured scenery our guidepost.
そうだ 傷ついた感情も連れて行くから
That's right, I'll bring along even my wounded feelings.
そっと響くカンパネラ 新しい未来を感じてる
The softly echoing campanella—I can feel a new future.
怖くたって進むしかないでしょ 遠くまで
Even if I'm scared, I have to keep moving forward, far away.
届けこの祈りよ 光に包まれ
Reach out, this prayer, wrapped in light.
もっと もっと 少しずつでもいい 私という答えを
More and more, even if little by little, the answer that is "me."
もっと...
More...
なぜだろう？教えて 私の証は
Why is that? Tell me, will the proof of my existence...
輝くの？教えて 見つけたい 見つけたいよ
...shine? Teach me, I want to find it, I want to find it.
誰かの決めたレールは 苦しくなるだけ
The rails set by someone else only bring pain.
ねぇ いつも力に変えるよ 心に誓い
Hey, I'll always turn it into strength, swearing in my heart.
錆びついた運命の歯車を回そう
Let's turn the rusted gears of fate.
ほら 着飾った感情は脱ぎ捨てるから
Look, I'll shed these dressed-up feelings.
そっと紡ぐしずくは 叶えたい願いを信じてる
The softly spun droplets believe in the wish I want to grant.
胸を張って歌うしかないでしょ 全力で
I have to stand proud and sing with all my strength.
不確定な希望の歌に変わる日まで
Until the day it turns into an uncertain song of hope.
もっと もっと 叫びながらでいい 全てが宝物
More and more, shouting is fine, everything is a treasure.
ありがとう！今日も楽しんでいってねー！
Thank you! Please have fun today too!
いつの日かこの声を 受け取ってくれたなら
If someday you receive this voice of mine,
この言葉を君に 「もう大丈夫 一人じゃない」
I give these words to you: "It's okay now, you are not alone."
強い思いをつなぐよ
I will connect these strong feelings.
一歩踏み出してみた 優しく世界は微笑む
Taking a step forward, the world gently smiles.
高なる気持ちに身を任せて さあ行こう
Surrendering to my surging heart, come on, let's go!
そっと響くカンパネラ 新しい未来を感じてる
The softly echoing campanella—I can feel a new future.
怖くたって進むしかないでしょ 遠くまで
Even if I'm scared, I have to keep moving forward, far away.
届けこの祈りよ 光に包まれ
Reach out, this prayer, wrapped in light.
もっと もっと 少しずつでもいい 私という答えを
More and more, even if little by little, the answer that is "me."
もっと...
More...
この扉の向こうが 未知の可能性なら
If beyond this door lies unknown possibilities,
今を動かせるの？
can I move the present?
暗闇を手探りで 不安と焦燥の中
Fumbling in the dark amid anxiety and impatience,
こぼれる光を見た
I saw a spilling ray of light.
手を伸ばして この先は君...
Reaching out my hand, beyond here is you...
生物だから
Because we are living things,
遠くを こうやって
across the distance, like this,
繋がるよ ここがいま
we connect right here, right now.
そう ざわざわするの 私のストーリー
Yes, my story is stirring with excitement.
ごめん 焦らせて 君を知りたいから
Sorry for rushing you, but I want to know you.
輝かせよう 新しい世界
Let's make a new world shine.
生まれた意味を見つけるのさ
I'll find the meaning of why I was born.
すべてが始まる この場所で
In this place where everything begins,
声が枯れるまで 叫んで
shout until your voice goes hoarse!
答え教えてよ 夜のメランコリー
Tell me the answer, nighttime melancholy.
イエーイ！
Yeah!
身体と感情が 交差する
My body and emotions intersect.
ただ信じる 自分はなに？
What is the "me" that I simply believe in?
意図をつないで 交差する
Connecting intentions, they intersect.
世界は ひとつじゃない
The world isn't just one.
いいねとファボの数字 増えていく
The numbers of likes and faves keep increasing.
盲目に正論 振りかざして 首を締める
Blindly brandishing sound arguments, choking ourselves.
私の生きる世界は
The world I live in,
自分の手で選ばせてよ
let me choose it with my own hands.
真夜中のメランコリー 生まれ変わるアイデンティティ
Midnight melancholy, a reborn identity.
この身が この変化が 痛いよ
This body, this change, it hurts.
上辺だけの泣きストーリー 執着していく可愛いフェイス
A superficial sob story, obsessed with a cute face.
私は 私は
Am I... am I...
誰かにとって 変わるの？
changing for someone else?
どんどん行くよー！
Let's keep going!
みんな手たたいてー！
Everyone, clap your hands!
どうして 気づいてしまったの
Why did I end up noticing?
熱くなる頬に
On my blushing cheeks,
隠しきれない戸惑い
a bewilderment I can't hide.
ギクシャクした距離
An awkward distance,
あやふやにして
leaving it vague,
揺れる心
my wavering heart,
バレないように
so nobody finds out.
人知れず 響く胸の鼓動
Unnoticed by anyone, my heart pounds.
こうやって 息することすらままならないのに
Even though I can barely breathe like this...
きっとどこかで 願っているんだ
Surely somewhere, I'm wishing for it—
終わりのない時間を
an endless time.
恋の始まりは 誰も知らない
Nobody knows when love begins,
私だけの 宝物を
a treasure that belongs only to me.
少しでも 言葉にできたなら
If I could express even a little bit in words,
日だまりのような笑顔も
a sunny smile,
土砂降りの泣き顔も 全部
or a tearful face like a downpour, all of it,
眩しくしてしまいそうで
feels like it might turn dazzlingly bright.
もしもひとつだけ 叶うのならば
If just one wish could come true,
ただ君のすぐとなりで
right beside you,
過ぎていく季節 眺めていたい
I want to watch the passing seasons.
あふれそうなこの思いは
These feelings that seem about to overflow,
胸の奥にしまい込んだ
I tucked them deep inside my heart.
ふたりの声が 空に吸い込まれていく
Our two voices get sucked up into the sky.
閉ざした世界 かすかに聞こえる音
In a closed-off world, a faintly audible sound.
世界でふたり 切り取った
Just the two of us, cut off from the world.
届きそうで すれ違った鼓動が
Heartbeats that seemed reachable, yet passed each other by,
ちょっと頼りない
feel a little unreliable.
ここで待って
Wait for me here,
wait for me here,
ここで待って
wait for me here.
決められないままで
Remaining unable to decide,
戸惑い溢れてしまうよ
my confusion overflows.
もう何度も 繰り返した
I've repeated this so many times already.
こぼれた思いを数えて
Counting my spilled feelings,
何度も繰り返した
I repeated it over and over.
世界 世界 秘めたままで
Kept hidden from the world, the world...
まだまだ盛り上がっていくよ！
We're just getting started!
もっと声出せるよね！
You can make even more noise, right?!
馬鹿馬鹿しいな 不自由な思考
How ridiculous, these restricted thoughts,
意味がないなら 楽しい歌を
if they're meaningless, let me sing a fun song.
攻めてく人
Those who attack,
逃げてく人
those who run away,
良くない人に 生き苦しくなる
bad people make it suffocating to live.
前向きな夕暮れ
A forward-looking sunset...
狂った世界で僕らはみんな生きてるから
Because we're all living in this crazy world,
好きになったり殺してしまったり
falling in love, or destroying each other,
変わる目で 祈りのように
with changing eyes, like a prayer.
ニュースが流れ 大事件に
As news flows of major incidents,
涙を流す人はいない
nobody sheds a tear.
ビル街が 嘘の町
A cityscape of lies amidst skyscrapers,
さあ 抜け出して
come on, break out
光の街へ
into the city of light.
偽物ばかり
Nothing but fakes,
すべて 上辺で飾って ごまかして
decorating everything on the surface, deceiving,
何が正解か分からないから 壊れていく
not knowing what the right answer is, breaking down.
一体何が本当なんだっけ？
What was actually real, anyway?
期待しても泣き濡れてばかり
Even if I hold out hope, I'm just soaked in tears,
傷をも巻いて 始末するよ
I'll wrap up my wounds and settle it all.
こんな異常だらけの世界で
In a world full of anomalies like this,
存在を探しているんだ
I'm searching for my existence.
覚悟のわりに
Despite my resolve,
自由になりやどこですか？
where do I go to become free?
こんな異常だらけの世界で 存在を探しているんだ
In a world full of anomalies like this, I'm searching for my existence.
何を言われても
No matter what anyone says,
満たされることないよ
I'll never be satisfied.
感覚すらも
Even my senses...
すべて忘れて...
forget everything...
はい！ えーということで...
All right! So...
AZKi ソロライブ 2025「Departure」へようこそ！
Welcome to AZKi Solo Live 2025 "Departure"!
ちょっとぶっ飛ばしすぎた... ぶっ飛ばしました！
I went a bit too fast... I really rushed into it!
あー 見渡す限り 超満員！
Ah, as far as the eye can see, it's packed!
本当にもうね、この景色を見て、もう感極まってしまっているんですが...
Honestly, seeing this view makes me so overwhelmed with emotion...
えー、みんな本当に今日来てくれてありがとうございます！
Everyone, thank you so much for coming today!
今日はAZKiにとって初めてのアリーナでのソロライブです！
Today is AZKi's very first solo live in an arena!
この景色... 本当に胸がいっぱいで... まだ早いか！ この段階は！
This view... my heart is so full... Wait, it's too early for this stage!
ということで、みんな今日は貴重な1日をAZKiのライブのために時間を作ってくれてありがとうございます！
So, thank you all so much for taking time out of your precious day for AZKi's live!
早速なんですが、ぶっ飛ばしましたね！ メドレー、どうでしたー？
Right off the bat, I really charged ahead, didn't I? How was the medley?!
ありがとうございます！ そしてね、もちろん1曲目はこの曲と決めていました『未来カンパネラ』ということで...
Thank you! And of course, I had decided the first song had to be "Mirai Campanella"...
新EPの『Re:Start』から1曲お届けしましたが... みんな！ EPは聴いてくれましたかー？！
I delivered a song from my new EP, "Re:Start"... Everyone! Have you listened to the EP?!
あー、ありがとうございますー！
Ah, thank you so much!
そして！ そして！ 本日の衣装、どうですかー？
And! And! How do you like today's outfit?!
可愛いですかー？ 早速ね、キービジュアルでみんなも「この衣装で来るんじゃないか」と思ってたと思うんですけど...
Is it cute? I bet everyone saw the key visual and thought, "She'll probably wear this outfit," right?
なんと...
And as it turns out...
イメージして
With that image in mind,
黒のカラーバリエーションも作っていただきました！
they also made a black color variation for me!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
そして今日ね、素敵なステージでございます！
And today, we have this wonderful stage!
みんな、上部の装飾気づきました？
Everyone, did you notice the decorations at the top?
変化してたの気づきました？この上のね、この今、アルファっていう
Did you notice it changing? This part above, right now it says "alpha"...
お、お、あ、ピカピカピカピカ！
Oh, oh, ah! Sparkle, sparkle, sparkle, sparkle!
ありがとうございます！この変化気づきましたでしょうか？
Thank you so much! Did you notice this change?
曲のね、頭で実はあの、このアルファの装飾部分がですね
Actually, at the beginning of the song, this alpha decoration part...
あの、色が変わっていまして
well, its color changed...
みんなちょっとあの、続いてこれ大変だったよね、この色にしてくださいっていう
everyone... continuing from that, it was tough, right? Asking to "make it this color"...
ペンライトカラーになっておりました！
it turned into the penlight color!
本当に曲の冒頭の方なので、あの、見れた方は
It was really right at the beginning of the song, so if you saw it...
ありがとう！あの、変えていただけたらなと思います
thank you! I hope you were able to change your penlight colors.
それに合わせてね、みんなのペンライト点灯していただいたり、2色
Matching that, you illuminated your penlights, or when two colors...
光った時はですね、ペンライトも2色にしてください！
glowed, please set your penlights to two colors as well!
みんなで一緒に今日のライブ作っていこう！よろしくお願いします！
Let's create today's live concert together, everyone! Thank you!
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you so much!
ということで、今日のライブはですね、バンドメンバーと一緒にお届けしております！
So, for today's live concert, I'm performing together with the band members!
すごい、素晴らしい演奏ありがとうございます！
Wow, thank you so much for the wonderful performance!
しかも！なんと、今回はですね、バイオリンも参加しております！
And what's more! This time, we also have a violin joining us!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
今日のために特別にアレンジした楽曲もたくさんあるので
We have many songs specially arranged for today, so...
お楽しみに！
look forward to them!
そして、今日はね、現地のみんなだけじゃなくてですね
And today, it's not just everyone here at the venue, but...
配信で見てくれる開拓者もいます！
there are also Pioneers watching on the livestream!
配信のみんなー！
Everyone on the stream!
はい、コメントも見えてる！おー、イエー！
Yes, I can see the comments too! Oh, yeah!
AZKiちー！ふー、イエー！あおりんがすごい！
AZKi-chi! Woo, yeah! The cheering is amazing!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
ということで、本日は、ハッシュタグ
So, today, using the hashtag...
#AZKiと未来へ で今日の感想や
#AZKiと未来へ , please post your impressions of today...
印象に残った瞬間をポストしてください！後で全部見に行きます！
and your memorable moments! I'll go check them all out later!
よろしく！配信の皆、スクショもよろしく！
Thank you! Everyone on stream, feel free to take screenshots too!
そして、皆様
And, to everyone...
YouTubeやTikTokでご覧の皆様！
watching on YouTube or TikTok!
残念ながら... おしゃべり早い！
Unfortunately... My talking was too fast!
無料チラ見せはここまで！
The free sneak peek ends here!
ありがとうございます！現地の声援もいただきまして
Thank you so much! Thank you for the cheers from the venue too,
まだまだ一緒に盛り上がりたいみんなは
and for everyone who wants to keep hyping up with me,
概要欄のリンクから配信サイトへ飛べますので
you can go to the streaming sites via the link in the description,
ここからが本番なので！たくさんの人に見てもらいたいなと思っています！
so because the main part starts now, I hope many people will watch it!
今回のライブなんですが
For this concert...
これまでAZKiが歩んできた軌跡、そして
it's the trajectory that AZKi has walked so far, and...
これから歩んでいく未来、その全てをみんなと一緒に1つの物語として
the future we will walk from now on, connecting all of that together with everyone...
繋いでいくような1日にしたいと思っています
as one single story for this day.
このライブで私の「今」
In this concert, I want to straight up...
の全てを音楽とともにまっすぐみんなに届けていきます！よろしくお願いします！
deliver my "present" self, along with the music, to all of you! Thank you!
それじゃあ、どんどん行きますよ！
Alright then, let's keep going!
最後まで一緒に楽しんでいこうね！
Let's enjoy this together until the very end!
一緒に歌って！
Sing together with me!
みんなの声聴かせて！
Let me hear everyone's voices!
無料パートは終了いたしました！ご視聴ありがとうございました！
[Text: The sneak peek part of the show has ended. Thank you for watching!]